Nancy Hale Papers, 1908-1989
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE
  - General
    - Photocopies of Nancy Hale to May Sarton circa 1941-82, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Scott, Eleanor and Fred 1968-80, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Scott, Shelah 1984-88, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Sergeant, Elizabeth S. 1960-64 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Shannon, Eleanor and Edgar 1974-87, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Skinner, Cornelia Otis 1962 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Sloane, William 1964-74 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Sophia Smith Collection 1963-86, undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Steele, Paul C. 1964-66 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Stegner, Wallace 1971, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Stillman, Chauncey 1975-84, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Stites, Clara Perkins 1924, undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Swaine, Bill 1973-74 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - T 1934-88, undated (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Tate, Allen 1962, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Thaxter, Katharine 1945, 1983-86, undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Toynbee, Philip 1947 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Travers, P.L. 1967-69, undated (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Turnbull, Andrew 1963-64 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - U - V 1959-84, undated (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Updike, John 1962 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Virginia Center for the Creative Arts 1976-87 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Virginia, Commonwealth of 1972-87 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Virginia Cultural Laureate Center 1981 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Virginia, University of 1961-85, undated (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Virginia, University of, Art Museum 1975-86, undated (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - W 1940-88, undated (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
    - Warner, Sylvia Townsend 1965-79 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Welty, Eudora 1967 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Wertenbaker, Lael 1948-88, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
      [see also Fletcher, Lael Wertenbaker]
    - West, Conn 1980-87 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - West, Jessamyn 1980 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Westreich, Michael 1980-88, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Whitcomb, John 1978-83 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - White, Katharine S. and E.B. 1938-77 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Whitehill, Jane 1960-73 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Whitlow, Amanda 1982-83 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Williams, Joan 1960, 1982-88 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Wilson, Robert Gould 1981 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Wilson, Edmund 1968 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Winsor School 1973-85 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Winsor School gift of property in Eastham, MA, 1972, 1981-84 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Y - Z 1937-84, undated (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Yates, Richard 1960-66 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Ziegel, Liliane 1971-79, undated (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - First name only (A - Z) and unidentified 1921-88, undated (Box 18, Folder 21-33)
    - Outgoing, miscellaneous 1950s-75, undated (Box 18, Folder 34)
- SERIES III. DIARIES, CALENDARS, AND NOTEBOOKS
  - Line-a-day, 1917; "Club Book, Cook Book, and Story Book of Nancy Hale and her friends of the HSH Club" 1917-28 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Diary 1919 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - "Good Times Record of Nancy Hale" 1921-25 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Diary and account book 1922-23 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - "Beaux" book 1922-27 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Diaries 1925-1927 (Box 19, Folder 6-8)
  - Breakdown notes 1938 (Box 19, Folder 9-10)
  - Diaries 1939-41 (Box 19, Folder 11-12)
  - Diary 1942 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - "Minor Road Thoughts" circa 1942-48 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Diary 1943 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Breakdown notes 1943 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Engagement calendars 1948-56 (Box 20, Folder 5-9)
  - Pocket diary 1959 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Engagement calendars 1961-62 (Box 20, Folder 11-12)
  - Engagement calendars 1963-64 (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
  - Pocket calendars 1964/65-1965/66 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Engagement calendars 1965-66 (Box 21, Folder 4-5)
  - Pocket calendars 1966/67-1973/74, 1975/76 (Box 21, Folder 6-8)
  - Wall engagement calendar 1988 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous notebooks undated (Box 21, Folder 10-11)
  - Notes on dreams undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Commonplace book undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
- SERIES IV. PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Nancy Hale--alone 1908-88 (Box 22, Folder 1-11)
  - Family
    - Nancy and Lilian Westcott Hale [mother] 1908-50s (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Nancy and Philip L. Hale [father] 1908-11 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Nancy Hale and nurses circa 1908-09 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Hardin
      - Taylor Scott Hardin [first husband] 1910s-30s (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Nancy Hale and Taylor Scott Hardin wedding 1928 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Mark Hardin (son) circa 1930-88 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Nancy Hale and Mark Hardin 1930s-80s (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Hardin granddaughters 1960s-86 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Hardin granddaughters with great-grandchildren of Nancy Hale 1980s (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Wertenbaker
      - Nancy Hale and Charles Wertenbaker (second husband) 1935 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - William Wertenbaker (son) 1938-circa 1962 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Nancy Hale and William Wertenbaker 1940-60s (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Lilian W. Hale and William Wertenbaker 1940s (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - William and Julia (Cannon) Wertenbaker and family 1960s-80s (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Fredson Bowers (third husband) 1940s-87 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Nancy Hale and Fredson Bowers 1965-80 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Groups
      - With Nancy Hale 1908-87 (Box 23, Folder 14)
      - Nancy Hale, Mark Hardin, and William Wertenbaker 1939-40 (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Without Nancy Hale 1940-87 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Mark Hardin and William Wertenbaker 1939-47 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Other relatives 1910s-80s (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Friends and associates
    - Annie Richardson and family 1970s-80s (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Dramatics 1910s (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - At Folly Cove, Gloucester, MA 1920-70s (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - With Nancy Hale 1908-1980s (Box 24, Folder 8-11)
    - Without Nancy Hale 1910s-80s (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Winsor School 1920s, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Houses
    - Sandy Down, Dedham, MA 1924, 1940 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Howlets, Folly Cove, Gloucester, MA 1940s-80s (Box 24, Folder 15-16)
    - Virginia 1950s-70s (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous undated (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Portraits (artwork) of Nancy Hale undated (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Negatives, 1-90 (Box 25)
- SERIES V. SPEECHES
  - Texts and notes
    - "Analyzing Fiction" undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - "Autobiography" undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Being a woman writer 1963 (Book and Author Luncheon, Baltimore, MD) (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - "The Boston Girl" circa 1970 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - "Character" (Bread Loaf Writers' Conference) undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - "Character and Thomas Wolfe" 1962 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - "Communicating and Being Communicated With" undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - "Content in Fiction" (Bread Loaf Writers' Conference) undated (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - "Creativity" undated (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - "An End of Fiction" (American Psychiatric Association) 1976 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - "A Fiction Writer Faces Facts," (Alexandria Library) 1964 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - "Getting Ideas" (Bread Loaf Writers' Conference): notes undated (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Introduction for Virginia Mishnun-Hardman undated (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Introduction for Virginia Moore 1977 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - "Lying Fallow" (Bread Loaf Writers' Conference) undated (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - "Magic Heroes and Practical Saviours" 1971 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - "Novel vs. Short Story" (Bread Loaf Writers' Conference) undated (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - "Flannery O'Connor: Prodigal Daughter's Return" 1971
      - Drafts (Box 26, Folder 18)
      - Fragments (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - "Plot" (Bread Loaf Writers' Conference) undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - "The Other Side of the Rotunda" (University of Virginia Commencement Address) 1975 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Scribners' undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - "The Short Story" (Bread Loaf Writers' Conference) 1962 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - "The Territory of Fiction" (Bread Loaf Writers' Conference) undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - "Through the Looking Glass to Reality" undated (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Tribute to Maizie Cash undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - "The Two-Way Imagination" (Abernethy Lecture, Middlebury College) 1960 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Center for the Creative Arts undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Cultural Development Study Commission testimony 1967 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - "What it Means to be Creative" (Bread Loaf Writers' Conference) undated (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Winsor School class of 1926, 25th reunion, 1951 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Writing novels undated (Bread Loaf Writers' Conference) (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous unidentified notes for lectures, undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, programs, and clippings
    - General 1937-82, undated (Box 28, Folder 8-11)
    - Bread Loaf Writers' Conference 1960-66 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Phi Beta Kappa Visiting Scholars Program 1970-72 (Box 28, Folder 13-15)
    - University of Virginia Commencement Address 1975 (Box 28, Folder 16)
- SERIES VI. SUBJECT FILES (1927-88, n.d.)
  - Authors Guild of America, Inc. 1962-75 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Award/Contest judging 1967-82 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Dyslexia 1983, 1988, undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Folly Cove, Gloucester, MA 1978, undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Ann Hobson Freeman and George 1966-84, undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Hale House, Roxbury, MA undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - HEW Advisory Committee on New Educational Media, 1964-65, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - League of Women Voters of Albemarle County, VA 1958 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - MacDowell Colony 1965-85, undated (Box 29, Folder 9-10)
  - People, misc. 1927-83, undated (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - P.E.N. (Poetry, Essays, and Novels) 1960-85 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Stowe-Day Foundation 1976-83 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Virginia Commission of the Arts and Humanities 1967-69 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Virginia Center for the Creative Arts 1971-89 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Winsor School 1968-88, undated (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Writing 1977, undated (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Writing as therapy 1969-70 (Box 29, Folder 18)
- SERIES VII. WRITINGS
  - Agents
    - David Higham Associates, London 1960-78 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Harold Ober Associates 1954-88 (Box 30, Folder 2-12)
    - Elizabeth Nowell
      - Correspondence with Nancy Hale
        - 1935-50 (Box 30, Folder 13-18)
        - 1951-57 (Box 31, Folder 1-7)
      - Correspondence with others
        - A 1949-56, undated (Box 31, Folder 8)
        - A. Sijthoff 1953-55 (Box 31, Folder 9)
        - Authors and Publishers International Agency (APIA) 1950-57 (Box 31, Folder 10)
        - Authors' League of America 1949-53 (Box 31, Folder 11)
        - B 1950-57 (Box 31, Folder 12)
        - Bookman Literary Agency 1950-55 (Box 31, Folder 13)
        - C 1950-56 (Box 31, Folder 14)
        - Charles Scribner's Sons
          - 1949-55 (Box 31, Folder 15-20)
          - 1956-57 (Box 32, Folder 1-2)
        - D - F 1950-57 (Box 32, Folder 3)
        - Flair 1950, undated (Box 32, Folder 4)
        - Carlota Frahm 1951 (Box 32, Folder 5)
        - G 1950, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 6)
        - Good Housekeeping 1951, 1955, undated (Box 32, Folder 7)
        - Gyldendal-Bonnier-Hasselbach 1950-51 (Box 32, Folder 8)
        - H 1950-56 (Box 32, Folder 9)
        - Robert Harben 1950-51 (Box 32, Folder 10)
        - Harold Ober Associates 1950-57 (Box 32, Folder 11)
        - Harper's Bazaar 1949-57 (Box 32, Folder 12)
        - Franz Horch 1950-55 (Box 32, Folder 13)
        - L 1950-57 (Box 32, Folder 14)
        - Ladies' Home Journal 1950-54 (Box 32, Folder 15)
        - Library of Congress 1940, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 16)
        - Heinz Liepman 1950-56 (Box 32, Folder 17)
        - M 1950-57 (Box 32, Folder 18)
        - Ruth May, 1950 (Box 32, Folder 19)
        - Mondadori Publishing Company, Inc. 1950-56 (Box 32, Folder 20)
        - National Broadcasting Company 1955 (Box 32, Folder 21)
        - New Yorker 1949-57 (Box 32, Folder 22-25)
        - Permabooks 1953-57, undated (Box 32, Folder 26)
        - P - R 1950-56 (Box 32, Folder 27)
        - Pearn, Pollinger & Higham, Ltd. 1950-57 (Box 32, Folder 28-31)
        - Redbook 1949-50 (Box 32, Folder 32)
        - Russell & Volkening, Inc. 1949-55 (Box 32, Folder 33)
        - S 1949-55 (Box 32, Folder 34)
        - T - V 1950-57 (Box 32, Folder 35)
        - Today's Woman 1949-53, undated (Box 32, Folder 36)
        - Town and Country 1951-55, undated (Box 32, Folder 37)
        - T.P. Toth Verlag 1951, 1958 (Box 32, Folder 38)
        - University of Kansas City Review 1953-55 (Box 32, Folder 39)
        - Vassar College 1951 (Box 32, Folder 40)
        - Vogue 1956, undated (Box 32, Folder 41)
        - W 1950-56 (Box 32, Folder 42)
        - William Heinemann, Ltd. 1950-52 (Box 32, Folder 43)
        - Woman's Home Companion 1950-54, undated (Box 32, Folder 44)
        - X - Z 1949, 1951 (Box 32, Folder 45)
        - Unidentified 1951, undated (Box 32, Folder 46)
    - Russell & Volkening, Inc. 1948 (Box 32, Folder 47)
  - Publishers
    - Correspondence
      - Miscellaneous A - Z 1932-88 (Box 33, Folder 1-3)
      - Addison-Wesley Publishing Co. 1986-87 (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc. 1961-78 (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - Algonquin Books of Chapel Hill 1985-86 (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - Charles Scribner's Sons 1931-44, 1955 (Box 33, Folder 7-8)
      - Coward-McCann, Inc. 1969-77 (Box 33, Folder 9-10)
      - Doubleday & Company, Inc. 1965-82 (Box 33, Folder 11)
      - Gallimaufry 1977 (Box 33, Folder 12)
      - Harcourt, Brace & World 1966-70 (Box 33, Folder 13)
      - Harper/Harper & Row 1928, 1961-76 (Box 33, Folder 14)
      - Houghton, Mifflin Company 1960-69, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 15)
      - Howland & Company 1979-80 (Box 33, Folder 16)
      - Little, Brown and Company, Inc. 1960-71 (Box 33, Folder 17)
      - New Yorker 1933-88, undated (Box 34, Folder 1)
        [see also SERIES II: CORRESPONDENCE, General, Maxwell, William]
      - New York Times Book Review 1969-79 (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - Saturday Evening Post 1933, 1960-61 (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - Virginia Quarterly Review 1955-84, undated (Box 34, Folder 4)
      - W.W. Norton & Co., Inc. 1971-76 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Agreements and contracts
      - Charles Scribner's Sons 1933-56, undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Conde Nast 1934 (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - Coward-McCann, Inc. undated (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - Doubleday & Company, Inc. 1970, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - Editorial Poseidon 1943 (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Greenwood Press 1976 (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - Hearst Corporation, Avon Books 1964 (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - Little, Brown and Company, Inc. 1962 (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - Lovat Dickson Ltd. 1936 (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - Macmillan and Co., Ltd. 1960-63 (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - Marianne Brown Waters 1940 (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - NAL Penguin 1987 (Box 35, Folder 12)
      - New Yorker 1955-84 (Box 35, Folder 13)
      - Simon & Schuster, Pocket Books 1976 (Box 35, Folder 14)
      - Victor Gollancz Ltd. 1963 (Box 35, Folder 15)
      - William Heinemann, Ltd. 1951 (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Royalty Reports
      - Bell Syndicate, Inc. 1942 (Box 35, Folder 17)
      - Charles Scribner's Sons 1932-76 (Box 35, Folder 18)
      - Coward-McCann/Coward, McCann & Geoghegan 1963-82 (Box 35, Folder 19)
      - Doubleday & Company, Inc. 1971-87 (Box 35, Folder 20)
      - Greenwood Press 1976-87 (Box 35, Folder 21)
      - Hearst Corporation, Avon Books 1964-87 (Box 35, Folder 22)
      - Houghton, Mifflin 1954-86 (Box 35, Folder 23)
      - Little, Brown & Company 1960-82 (Box 35, Folder 24)
      - Macmillan & Company, Ltd. 1961-88 (Box 35, Folder 25)
      - New Yorker 1953-88 (Box 35, Folder 26)
      - Victor Gollancz, Ltd. 1962-69 (Box 35, Folder 27)
      - William Heinemann, Ltd. 1952-53 (Box 35, Folder 28)
      - Miscellaneous publishers, A - Z 1956-87 (Box 35, Folder 29)
  - Early writings
    - Correspondence with publishers 1919-20 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Notebooks and fragments undated (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Plays undated (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Poems and other short pieces 1920-25, undated (Box 36, Folder 4-5)
    - The Society Cat: issues and correspondence 1919-20 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Stories 1919, undated (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Articles
    - Miscellaneous
      - Short articles, pieces, and letters to editors 1929-76, undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - New Yorker 1933-34, undated (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - Vogue 1929-33, undated (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - "Can Writers Ignore Critics?" (Saturday Review of Literature, 1968): drafts, and published versions 1968 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - "Col. Sartoris and Mr. Snopes" (Vogue, Aug 1964): drafts, and clippings 1963 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - "Daughter of Abolitionists" (Sophia Smith Collection keepsake, 1964): draft 1964 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - "The Discomforts of Home": typescript undated (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - "A Fiction Writer Faces Facts" (Saturday Review, 12 Jun 1965): published version 1965 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Finns in granite industry in Massachusetts (Red Book, Mar 1937): clipping and translation 1937 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - F. Scott Fitzgerald keepsake (proposed Univ. of Virginia, 1970): correspondence, notes, and research material 1970 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - "Nathan Hale" (Defense Series pamphlet, 1941): correspondence, drafts and notes 1941 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Hale, Philip L.: typescript circa 1931 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - "A Handful of Rs" (Vogue (1 Nov 1961): typescript 1961 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - "Hemingway and the Courage to Be" (Virginia Quarterly Review, 1962): drafts, notes, and published version 1962 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - "The Hidden Approach" n.d.: typescript undated (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - "Hinkle, Beatrice" (Dictionary of American Biography, 1976) 1976
      - Drafts (Box 37, Folder 16)
      - Research material (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - "How to Keep From Writing" (Saturday Review of Literature, 7 Apr 1962): published version, and correspondence 1962 (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - Kabak, Robert, paintings (Angeleski Gallery n.d.): draft and mimeograph undated (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - "Language as a Vessel of Meaning" (proposed chapter for proposed book): correspondence and research material 1972-73 (Box 37, Folder 20)
    - "Lying Fallow" (The Writer, 1945): draft and published version 1945 (Box 37, Folder 21)
    - "The Magic of Creativity" (Saturday Evening Post, 29 Apr 1961): typescript and published version 1961 (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - "Notes While Trying to Get to Work" (Authors Guild Bulletin, 1966): drafts and published version 1966 (Box 37, Folder 23)
    - Harold Ober: draft undated (Box 37, Folder 24)
    - "The Other Side of the Cove": draft, notes, page proofs (Poetry 1960 or 1961 (Box 37, Folder 25)
    - "A Passage to Relationship" (Antioch Review, spring 1960): draft, published version 1960 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - "The Public Library Belongs to Us" (Newsletter of the Friends of the McIntire Public Library, 1964): draft and published version 1964 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Repertory theater in Boston: notes and drafts 1963? (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - "Cathe Wallendahl": draft and published version 1977 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - "What, This Old Thing?" (Authors Guild Bulletin, 1962): draft and published version 1962 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - "Wing, Virginia": draft and correspondence 1988 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Winsor School: drafts 1977 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Woolf, Virginia: drafts undated (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Wylie, Elinor: typescript circa 1930 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Book Reviews and introductions
    - Book Reviews
      - Correspondence and drafts, miscellaneous reviews 1968-72, undated (Box 38, Folder 10)
      - Bowen, Elizabeth, The Little Girls undated (Box 38, Folder 11)
      - Calisher, Hortense, Textures of Life (New York Times Book Review, 1963): drafts, notes, and published version 1963 (Box 38, Folder 12)
      - Colette (The Other Woman, Places, and Journey for Myself (New York Times Book Review, 1972): drafts and published version 1972 (Box 38, Folder 13)
      - Delaney, Shelagh, Sweetly Sings the Donkey (Cosmopolitan, 1963): published version 1963 (Box 38, Folder 14)
      - Godden, Rumer, Five for Sorrow, Ten for Joy; and Jessamyn West, The Life I Really Lived (New York Times Book Review, 1979): drafts and published version 1979 (Box 38, Folder 15)
      - Grumbach, Doris, The Company She Kept: drafts 1967? (Box 38, Folder 16)
      - Howe, Helen, The Gentle Americans ((New York Times Book Review): correspondence, drafts, notes, and published version undated (Box 38, Folder 17)
      - Mathews, Nancy Mowll, ed., Cassatt and Her Circle (Journal of Archives of American Art, 1985): correspondence, drafts, notes, and published version 1985 (Box 38, Folder 18)
      - Nabokov, Vladimir, Pale Fire: drafts 1962? (Box 38, Folder 19)
      - Nemerov, Howard, Journal of the Fictive Life (Virginia Quarterly Review, 1966): drafts 1966 (Box 38, Folder 20)
      - Peabody, Miriam L., To Be Young Was Very Heaven: drafts 1969? (Box 38, Folder 21)
      - West, Jessamyn, autobiography: notes and drafts undated (Box 38, Folder 22)
      - West, Jessamyn, The Woman Said Yes (New York Times Book Review, 1976): correspondence, drafts, and notes 1976 (Box 38, Folder 23)
      - Wheelock, John Hall, ed. Letters of Maxwell E. Perkins (Virginia Quarterly Review, 1979): draft 1979 (Box 38, Folder 24)
    - Introductions
      - Hilli by Gurdon [?] (Ivan Obolensky, 1963): correspondence, drafts 1963 (Box 38, Folder 25)
      - New England (Time-Life Books, 1967): drafts, correspondence, and notes 1967 (Box 38, Folder 26)
      - A New England Boyhood by Edward Everett Hale (Little, Brown, 1964): notes and drafts 1964 (Box 38, Folder 27)
      - The Complete Peterkin Papers by Lucretia Peabody Hale (MC Co., 1960): drafts and partial book jacket 1960 (Box 38, Folder 28)
      - Stories From The Peterkin Papers by Lucretia Peabody Hale (Scholastic Book Services, 1964): correspondence, draft, and published version 1964 (Box 38, Folder 29)
  - Children's
    - Stories
      [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL, Family, Wertenbaker, William, Illustrated stories by Nancy]
      - "Birds in the House" (The Learning Center, Charlottesville, VA, 1985): correspondence, drafts, published version, and review 1985 (Box 38, Folder 30)
      - "Describing": drafts 1984 (Box 38, Folder 31)
      - "Dog": drafts undated (Box 38, Folder 32)
      - "Girl From the City": typescript undated (Box 38, Folder 33)
      - "Inside Tommy Boy": drafts undated (Box 38, Folder 34)
      - "The Lost Summer": drafts undated (Box 38, Folder 35)
      - "Pie" drafts and typescript undated (Box 38, Folder 36)
      - "Raccoon Is Back": drafts undated (Box 38, Folder 37)
      - "Sailing Lessons": drafts undated (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - "The Story of Rory": drafts undated (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - "A Strange House": drafts and typescript undated (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - "The Summer Without the Raccoon": drafts undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - "Tea Party": typescript undated (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - "Those Raccoons!" (The Learning Center of Charlottesville, VA, 1985): drafts and published version 1985 (Box 39, Folder 6)
      - "The Trap": drafts and typescript undated (Box 39, Folder 7)
      - "The Troubles of Elizabeth": drafts and typescript undated (Box 39, Folder 8)
      - "Trust": typescript undated (Box 39, Folder 9)
      - "Wags" (The Learning Center of Charlottesville, VA): drafts, published version, and typescript 1985 (Box 39, Folder 10)